hey everyone welcome back to testoster
automation playlist and we are talking
about the top 10 Tosca best practices
which you should Implement in your
workspace or project
so before we move forward I would like
you to subscribe to our channel so that
you don't miss out on all the videos
which are on this very topic if you have
not watched the previous videos go back
to our playlist and do watch all the
different videos we have done on the
Tosca best practices
now coming to the number eight best
practice which is recommended by try
centers is to merge duplicate modules
the reason is very simple
duplicate modules uh will only increase
your workspace size and in the long run
it is going to increase your maintenance
efforts
what you can do is you can use the merge
module feature which is available in
Tosca to find and merge all your
duplicate modules
now the question is why someone will
create duplicate modules
so probably when you are working alone
you will not come across the scenario
because you know what modules you have
created for your project or for your
application and you will not go ahead
and create a duplicate module which you
have already created
but what if you're working in a team
right so there are different team
members who are working on the same
application and then due to some lack of
best practices or in your project the
modules are not named correctly or
someone in your team is not able to find
a particular module right it may be
because there are lots of modules and
he's not able to find it or the names
are not represented correctly so
somebody is not sure whether that module
does what it is intended to do right
so generally people uh find it easier to
scan new modules and they keep on
creating new modules without even
searching whether that module already
exists in the project that in itself is
a mistake and which leads to this
particular problem where you have got
lots of duplicate modules now the result
of this issue is the workspace size
keeps on increasing and then it becomes
unmanageable and similarly if you have
to maybe migrate your modules or you
have to update some modules you have to
do it for all the different duplicate
modules which only increases the time
which you need to spend in order to
maintain all of these modules right
so it is best recommended that you do
this activity on a regular basis you
check for duplicate modules and if you
need to merge uh certain modules then go
ahead and merge them so that your
workspace contains only a unique and
efficient modules this will also make
your project more efficient right and if
different people are working on it then
everybody will be using a single module
rather than using the same modules but
they are duplicate in the workspace
right
so let's see with an example uh what I
am talking all about right I have
already shown you uh in a different
video how you can merge duplicate
modules but let's say it quickly again
so I'm back in Tosca and here uh what I
have done is I have scanned this
particular page okay uh it's a simple
login form with username password and
login button now what I've done is I
have scanned this twice so you can see
here this is the swag labs and this is
also the swaglabs module and the module
attributes are exactly the same username
password login right
so it doesn't make any sense to keep
both these modules in this particular
workspace right it is of no use and also
these are additional objects in the
workspace right so what we can do is we
can go to uh one of our modules okay if
we know that there is a duplicate we can
directly merge them if not we can go
ahead and click on find duplicate
modules okay and then it will show me
both the modules
and then I can select any one of them
and click on merge selected right
so what it will do it will take this
Source module and then it will merge it
into the target module right the target
module will not be changed uh and any
usage also which is present for Source
or Target
um it will be linked properly to the
Target module and then the source module
will be deleted right so a proper
cleanup is done by this module merge
assistant and it is very fast and it
also tells you which modules are
actually duplicates if you cannot find
them on your own right so this feature
is already provided by Tosca and you
should use it to implement this best
practice so that you don't have any
unnecessary modules lying in your
workspace which is uh
obviously going to impact your overall
performance of your Tosca project
because the workspace size when it
becomes too big your performance is
impacted
um your Tosca will start to load very
slowly your executions will be slower
all right so it will impact everything
else so you need to keep a check on your
workspace size always and this is one
ways of doing it okay
so that's all for this short video I
hope you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today keep watching out
for our Channel as we are going to bring
up many more videos related Tosca and
other automation tools
so until we meet again keep learning and
keep watching